双语特效字幕
“龙堡字幕组”携手“衣柜字幕组”诚挚奉献
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译    屈畅（ccxx）
校对    赵琳
狭海   The Narrow Sea
君临 King's Landing
时间轴    ren
Red Keep
红堡
时间轴   antares
美术   cc
美术   den
美术   悠
临冬城 Winterfell
监制    临冬城的狮子
后期   加文·维斯特林
后期   poplar
策划    baozhenyuawabi
绝境长城 the Wall
压制   麻绳力攻
人人网冰与火之歌公共主页
http://page.renren.com/601227719/index
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
龙堡字幕组  &  百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
维斯·多斯拉克
Vaes·Dothrak
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
《冰与火之歌》 改编
根据长篇小说
权力的游戏
第一季 第三集
龙堡字幕组 & 衣柜字幕组
第三集  “雪诺大人”
"Lord Snow"
欢迎您 史塔克大人
Welcome, Lord Stark.
派席尔大学士刚刚召集御前会议
Grand Maester Pycelle has called a meeting of the Small Council.
恭请您大驾光临
The honor of your presence is requested.
好好安顿我女儿 我会回来吃晚饭
Get the girls settled in. I'll be back in time for supper.
茉丹
临冬城的修女
- 乔里 帮我看好他们 - 是 大人
- And, Jory, you go with them. - Yes, my Lord.
乔里·凯索
史塔克家族的侍卫队长
您是否要换上更合适的衣服进宫…
If you'd like to change into something more appropriate...
艾德·史塔克
御前首相 临冬城公爵 昵称“奈德”
谢天谢地 你终于到了 史塔克
Thank the gods you're here, Stark.
朝廷是该找个严厉的北方人来整顿作风了
About time we had some stern, northern leadership.
你这算是在履行职责 保护王座么
About glad to see you're protecting the throne.
噢 那把又老又硬的椅子呀
Sturdy old thing.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
御林铁卫队长 王后的孪生弟弟 “弑君者”
我正在想 它究竟被多少国王的屁股磨过
How many Kings' asses have polished it, I wonder?
俗话怎么说来着？
Um, what's the line?
国王拉屎 首相收拾
The King shits and The Hand wipes.
完美无暇的盔甲
Very handsome armor.
- 连一道划痕都没有 - 是啊
- Not a scratch on it. - I know.
无数人冲我身上招呼 可惜都碰不着
People have been swinging at me for years, but they always seem to miss.
这只能说明你善于挑选对手
You've chosen your opponents wisely then.
算是优点之一吧
I have a knack for it.
在这个大厅里 你的心情一定很复杂吧？
It must be strange for you coming into this room.
那件事发生时 我就站在这里
I was standing right here when it happened.
他们很勇敢 我是指 你哥哥
He was very brave, your brother.
还有你父亲
Your father too.
他们不该那样死去
They didn't deserve to die like that.
谁也不该那样死去
Nobody deserves to die like that.
而你只是袖手旁观
But you just stood there and watched.
五百人站在这里袖手旁观
500 men just stood there and watched.
七大王国最有权势的贵族和骑士
All the great knights of the Seven Kingdoms--
你以为他们说过一句话 动过一根指头？
you think anyone said a word, lifted a finger?
不 史塔克大人
No, Lord Stark.
这个站满了五百人的大厅跟墓窖一样沉寂
500 men and this room was silent as a crypt.
当然 除了惨叫以外
Except for the screams, of course,
还有疯王的笑声
and the Mad King laughing.
后来
And later...
当我看着疯王死去时
when I watched the Mad King die,
我想起了他烧你父亲时的笑声…
I remembered him laughing as your father burned...
那有一丝正义的滋味
It felt like justice.
这就是你每晚讲给自己的睡前故事？
Is that what you tell yourself at night?
你是正义的使者？
You're a servant of justice?
你在疯王背后捅刀子
That you were avenging my father when you
是为了给我父亲报仇？
shoved your sword in Aerys Targaryen's back?
告诉我…
Tell me--
如果我向他当面挑战而不是“背后捅刀子”
if I'd stabbed the Mad King in the belly instead of the back,
你会更佩服我吗？
would you admire me more?
你真是他忠勇的卫士
You served him well
只在不危及自身的时候
when serving was safe.
史塔克大人
Lord Stark.
瓦里斯
太监 情报总管 “八爪蜘蛛”
瓦里斯大人
Lord Varys.
我听说了您在国王大道上遇到的麻烦事儿
I was grievously sorry to hear of your troubles on the Kingsroad.
我们都在祈祷乔佛里王子能早日康复
We are all praying for Prince Joffrey's full recovery.
你们应该为屠夫的学徒祈祷
A shame you didn't say a prayer for the butcher's son.
蓝礼！你气色不错
Renly! You're looking well.
您看起来却一脸倦容
And you look tired from the road.
蓝礼·拜拉席恩
风息堡公爵 国王幼弟
我本想让他们把会议推迟到明天 可…
I told them this meeting could wait another day, but--
可我们应该以国事为先
But we have a Kingdom to look after.
史塔克大人 这些年来我一直想见您
I've hoped to meet you for some time, Lord Stark.
凯特琳夫人应该向您提起过我吧？
No doubt Lady Catelyn has mentioned me.
她是提过 贝里席大人
She has, Lord Baelish.
如果我没记错 你也认识我哥哥布兰登
I understand you knew my brother Brandon as well.
培提尔·贝里席
财政大臣 “小指头”
我跟他很熟 至今身上都还留着他的纪念
All too well. I still carry a token of his esteem
从肚脐到锁骨
from navel to collarbone.
或许是你选错了决斗对象
Perhaps you chose the wrong man to duel with.
我选的对象可不是他 大人
It wasn't the man that I chose, my Lord.
我选的是凯特琳·徒利
It was Catelyn Tully.
一个值得男人拼搏的女人 相信您也同意
A woman worth fighting for, I'm sure you'll agree.
不好意思打断您 史塔克大人
I humbly beg your pardon, my Lord Stark.
派席尔国师
Grand Maester.
多少年过去啦？
How many years has it been?
- 当初您还年轻 - 当初您还在辅佐另一位国王
- You were a young man. - And you served another King.
派席尔
大学士
噢 我真健忘
Oh, how forgetful of me.
这个是您的了
This belongs to you, now.
我们开始吧？
Should we begin?
- 不等国王吗？ - 只怕等到凛冬降临之时
- Without the King? - Winter may be coming,
我老哥也不会赏脸现身
but I'm afraid the same cannot be said for my brother.
陛下有太多事情需要操心
His Grace has many cares.
所以便将鸡毛蒜皮小事交给我们
He entrusts some small matters to us
以减轻负担
that we might lighten the load.
我们就是传说中的御前杂务会
We are the Lords of Small Matters here.
我老哥指示我们举办盛大的比武竞技
My brother instructs us to stage a tournament
以庆祝史塔克大人出任首相
in honor of Lord Stark's appointment as Hand of the King.
要花多少钱？
Mmm, how much?
优胜者赏四万金龙币
40,000 gold dragons to the champion,
居次者赏两万金龙币
20,000 to the runner-up,
射箭优胜也是两万
20,000 to the winning archer.
国库出得起这笔钱？
Can the treasury bear such expense?
还不是得伸手借
I'll have to borrow it.
想必兰尼斯特家会很乐意援手
The Lannisters will accommodate, I expect.
反正已经欠了泰温大人三百万金龙
We already owe Lord Tywin three million gold.
再借个八万算什么？
What's another 80,000?
你说王室负债高达‘三百万’金币？
Are you telling me the crown is three million in debt?
目前王室负债总额超过六百万
I'm telling you the crown is six million in debt.
你怎么会让国库沦落到这般地步？
How could you let this happen?
财政大臣只管找钱
The Master of Coin finds the money.
花钱的是国王和首相
The King and The Hand spend it.
琼恩·艾林绝不会允许劳勃
I will not believe Jon Arryn
把国家搞破产
allowed Robert to bankrupt the realm.
艾林大人固然精打细算
Lord Arryn gave wise and prudent advice,
但恐怕国王陛下
but I fear his Grace
- 不见得都听从睿智的谏言 - 我老哥最讨厌所谓的‘数铜板’
- doesn't always listen. - "Counting coppers," he calls it.
我明天就去跟陛下谈
I'll speak to him tomorrow.
这么铺张浪费的比赛 国家可负担不起
This tournament is an extravagance we cannot afford.
谈谈当然好 不过我们还是先着手订个计划吧
As you will. But still, we'd best make our plans.
在我跟劳勃交涉之前
There will be no plans
统统搁下来
until I speak to Robert.
诸位大人 请原谅 我…
Forgive me, my Lords. I'm--
- 我长途跋涉 实在是累了 - 史塔克大人
- I had a long ride. - You are The King's Hand,
您是国王的首相 为您效劳是我们职责所在
Lord Stark, we serve at your pleasure.
- 噢！ - 忍着点 就快好了
- Ow! - Please, it's nearly healed.
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
大王子
- 这丑死了 - 伤疤是王者的证明
- It's ugly. - A King should have scars
你打败了一只冰原狼 你是你父亲一样的勇士
you fought off a direwolf. You're a warrior like your father.
不 我跟他不一样 我没打败任何东西
I'm not like him. I didn't fight off anything.
他咬我 我只会尖叫
It bit me and all I did was scream.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
王后
这事两个史塔克妞都看见了
And the two Stark girls saw it, both of them.
这并非事实 事实是你杀了那野兽
That's not true. You killed the beast.
念着父辈的交情才饶了那两个丫头
You only spared the girl because of the love your father bears her father.
不 我没有…
I didn't, I--
伊里斯·坦格利安在位时
When Aerys Targaryen sat on the Iron Throne,
你父亲不过是个反贼 叛徒
your father was a rebel and a traitor.
有朝一日你也会坐上铁王座 到时候你怎么说 历史就怎么写
Someday you'll sit on the throne and the truth will be what you make it.
我非娶她不可吗？
Do I have to marry her?
是的
Yes.
她那么年轻貌美
She's very beautiful and young.
你若不喜欢她 只需在重大场合把她牵出来溜溜
If you don't like her, you only need to see her on formal occasions
等时机成熟 再跟她造几位小王子 小公主
and when the time comes, to make little princes and princesses.
你想搞浓妆艳抹的妓女 就去搞浓妆艳抹的妓女
And if you'd rather fuck painted whores, you'll fuck painted whores.
你中意名门闺秀 就去找名门闺秀
And if you'd rather lie with noble virgins, so be it.
我的宝贝儿子 你是这世界的主人
You are my darling boy and the world will be
世界将围绕你旋转
exactly as you want it to be.
但你要向那史塔克女孩献献殷勤
Do something nice for the Stark girl.
- 我不想 - 你不想 但你得这么做
- I don't want to. - No, but you will.
在王者之路上 小恩小惠会为你扫清许多障碍
The occasional kindness will spare you all sorts of trouble down the road.
太纵容那些北方佬了
We allow the Northerners too much power.
他们自以为能跟我们平起平坐
They consider themselves our equals.
那你想怎么处理呢？
How would you handle them?
我要把他们的赋税加倍
I'd double their taxes
再命令他们交出一万名壮丁以组建王家军队
and command them to supply 10,000 men to the Royal Army.
王家军队？
A Royal Army?
凭什么每个领主都有权带兵？
Why should every lord command his own men?
这太原始了 跟山上的原住民有什么区别？
It's primitive, no better than the hill tribes.
我们应该建立一支忠于王室的常备军
We should have a standing army of men loyal to the crown,
由久经沙场的老兵训练
trained by experienced soldiers--
而不是临到头来征集一帮从没摸过刀枪的农民
instead of a mob of peasants who've never held pikes in their lives.
如果北方人不愿纳税交人呢？
And if the Northerners rebel?
那他们就是自取灭亡
I'd crush them.
我要攻占临冬城 任命一位大忠臣来当北境守护
Seize Winterfell and install someone loyal to the realm
比如凯冯舅公
as warden of the North. Uncle Kevan, maybe.
你觉得这一万北方精锐 到时候是为你而战还是支持自己的领主呢？
And these 10,000 Northern troops, would they fight for you or their lord?
当然是为我！我是他们的国王
For me. I'm their King.
可你是在侵略他们的家园
But you've just invaded their homeland,
- 你还要他们同室操戈 - 我不是要求他们 是…
- asked them to kill their brothers. - I'm not asking.
一个外来人可以征服北境 却无法保住北境
The North cannot be held-- not by an outsider.
它过于辽阔 又桀骜不驯
It's too big and too wild. And when the winter comes,
当北境的冬天到来时 恐怕七神加在一起也无法挽救你和你的王家军队
the Seven Gods together couldn't save you and your royal army.
真正的王者懂得何时蓄势
A good King knows when to save his strength...
何时克敌
And when to destroy his enemies.
这么说…
So you agree...
你也同意史塔克是敌人？
The Starks are enemies?
那当然了 非我族类
Everyone who isn't us
其心必异
is an enemy.
艾莉亚·史塔克
临冬城公爵次女
别敲了 小姐 赶紧吃东西
Enough of that, young lady. Eat your food.
- 我在练习 - 练什么
- I'm practicing. - Practicing for what?
- 练怎么杀王子 - 艾莉亚 你给我停下！
- The Prince. - Arya, stop!
他是个骗子 懦夫 他杀了我朋友
He's a liar and a coward and he killed my friend.
杀你朋友的是猎狗
The Hound killed your friend.
去！王子怎么吩咐 猎狗就怎么做
The Hound does whatever the Prince tells him to do.
你个白痴
You're an idiot.
你个骗子 如果你肯说实话
You're a liar, and if you told the truth
- 米凯就不会死了 - 够了！
- Mycah would be alive. - Enough!
怎么回事？
What's happening here?
艾莉亚太放肆了 没一点淑女样子
Arya would rather act like a beast than a lady.
回房去 我待会儿找你谈
Go to your room. We'll speak later.
给你 亲爱的
That's for you, love.
弥赛菈公主的玩具都是这位师傅做的
The same dollmaker makes all of Princess Myrcella's toys.
喜欢吗？
Don't you like it?
珊莎·史塔克
临冬城公爵长女
八岁起我就不玩娃娃了
I haven't played with dolls since I was eight.
- 我可以先告退吗? - 可你的东西几乎都没吃
- May I be excused? - You've barely eaten a thing.
没事 你去吧
It's all right. Go on.
养闺女比打仗还难哪
War was easier than daughters.
走开！
Go away!
艾莉亚 开门
Arya, open the door.
我可以进来吗？
May I come in?
- 这把剑是谁的？ - 我的
- Whose sword is that? - Mine.
给我
Give it to me.
我认得铸剑人的记号 这是密肯打的
I know this maker's mark. This is Mikken's work.
你怎么弄到这把剑的？
Where did you get this?
这可不是玩具
This is no toy.
小淑女是不该玩剑的
Little ladies shouldn't play with swords.
我才不是玩剑呢
I wasn't playing.
而且我不想变成淑女
And I don't want to be a lady.
过来
Come here.
你要它来做什么？
Now what do you want with this?
它叫缝衣针
It's called Needle.
啊 它还有名字…
Oh, a blade with a name.
你想拿这缝衣针来对付谁？
And who were you hoping to skewer with Needle?
你姐姐？
Your sister?
你知道剑道的第一课是什么？
Do you know the first thing about sword fighting?
用尖的那端去刺敌人
Stick 'em with the pointy end.
这的确是剑术的精髓
That's the essence of it.
我想好好学
I was trying to learn.
我要米凯陪我练
I asked Mycah to practice with me.
是我找他的
I asked him.
- 都是我的错 - 别这样 我亲爱的孩子
- It was my fault. - No, sweet girl.
不 不 屠夫小弟不是你害的
No no, you didn't kill the butcher's boy.
我恨他们！我恨死他们了！
I hate them! I hate all of them.
我恨猎狗 恨王后 恨国王
The Hound, the Queen and the King
还有乔佛里和珊莎
and Joffrey and Sansa.
珊莎是被拖到国王和王后面前的…
Sansa was dragged before the King and Queen...
你希望她指证王子？
And asked to call the Prince a liar.
我还不是被拖去的！而且他本来就是个大骗子！
So was I! He is a liar.
嘘 宝贝 听我说
Shh, darling, listen to me.
珊莎跟乔佛里订过婚
Sansa will be married to Joffrey's someday.
她不能出卖未来的夫婿
She cannot betray him.
即便他有千般不对 她也得站在他那边
She must take his side even when he's wrong.
可你怎能让她嫁给这种人？
But how you can let her marry someone like that?
好吧
Well.
看着我
Look me.
作为临冬城史塔克家族的一份子 你知道我们的族语
You're a Stark of Winterfell. You know our words.
凛冬将至
Winter is coming.
你生于漫长的盛夏时节
You were born in the long summer.
还未经历其他季节
You've never known anything else.
现在冬天真的要来了
But now winter is truly coming.
在冬天 我们必须保卫彼此
And in the winter, we must protect ourselves,
相互温暖 共享力量 珊莎她再怎么说也是你姐姐
look after one another. Sansa is your sister.
我不恨她
I don't hate her.
不是真的恨她
Not really.
我并非有意吓你
I don't want to frighten you,
然而我也不想骗你
but I won't lie to you either.
我们来到了一个危险的地方
We've come to a dangerous place.
我们不能自相残杀
We cannot fight a war amongst ourselves.
好吗？
All right?
拿去罢 这是你的了
Go on. It's yours.
我可以留着吗？
I can keep it?
别拿剑刺你姐姐就好
Try not to stab your sister with it.
你想留着它
If you're going to own a sword,
就得学会怎么用它
you'd better know how to use it.
布兰·史塔克
临冬城公爵次子
别听它叫唤 乌鸦就会说谎
Don't listen to it. Crows are all liars.
临冬城的老奶妈
- 我知道一个乌鸦的故事 - 我讨厌你那些故事
- I know a story about a crow. - I hete your stories.
我知道有个故事是讲讨厌听故事的小男孩
I know a story about a boy who hated stories.
我来说说“高个”邓肯爵士的故事吧
I could tell you about Ser Duncan the tall.
你最喜欢这个故事了
Those were always your favorites.
我最喜欢的才不是这个
Those weren't my favorites.
我喜欢的是那些吓人的
My favorites were the scary ones.
噢 我亲爱的孩子啊 你出生在夏季 哪里懂得真正的恐惧？
Oh, my sweet summer child. What do you know about fear?
当冬天来临
Fear is for the winter,
积雪百尺
when the snows fall a hundred feet deep.
当长夜漫漫
Fear is for the long night,
终年不见天日
when the Sun hides for years
小孩生于黑夜 长于黑夜
and children are born and live and die
死于黑夜
all in darkness.
当异鬼穿梭林间
That is the time for fear, my little lord,
那才是恐惧降临之时 小少爷
when the White Walkers move through the woods.
几千年前
Thousands of years ago there came a night
在一个长达一代人的长夜里
that lasted a generation.
城中的国王
Kings froze to death in their castles,
和茅屋里的羊倌同样颤抖着被冻死
same as the Shepherds in their huts.
母亲们宁可闷死自己的孩子
And women smothered their babies
也不愿见他们挨饿受冻
rather than see them starve,
她们放声大哭 眼泪却冻结在脸颊上
and wept and felt the tears freeze on their cheeks.
你喜欢听的就是这种故事？
So is this the sort of story that you like?
在一片黑暗中
In that darkness,
异鬼首度降临人间
the White Walkers came for the first time.
他们横扫城市和王国
They swept through cities and Kingdoms,
骑着死马
riding their dead horses,
带着大如猎狗的白蜘蛛四处狩猎…
hunting with their packs of pale spiders big as Hounds--
你在给他说什么呢?
What are you telling him now?
说小少爷爱听的故事啊
Only what what the little lord telling wants to hear.
去用晚餐吧 我想和他独处一会儿
Get your supper. I want some time with him.
罗柏·史塔克
临冬城公爵长子
从前她跟我讲
One time she told me
天空之所以是蓝色的
the sky is blue because we live inside the eye
全因我们住在蓝眼巨人马克比的眼睛里
of a blue-eyed giant named Macomber.
或许真是这样呢
Maybe we do.
你感觉如何？
How do you feel?
还是什么也不记得？
You still don't remember anything?
布兰
Bran,
我见你爬过上千回了
I've seen you climb a thousand times.
在风中 在雨中…
In the wind, in the rain--
上千回地爬
a thousand times.
- 你从没失足 - 可我确实摔下来了
- You never fall. - I did though.
是真的 是不是？
It's true, isn't it,
鲁温师傅说我的腿…
what Maester Luwin says about my legs?
我宁愿去死
I'd rather be dead.
- 永远不要说这种话 - 我宁愿去死
- Don't ever say that. - I'd rather be dead.
由这道门进出的人比较少 夫人
Fewer eyes back here, my Lady.
凯特琳·徒利
临冬城公爵夫人
但还是不能大意
But still too many.
我已经阔别都城九年了
It's nine years since I've set foot in the capital.
罗德利克·凯索
临冬城教头
即便九年前也没几个人知道我是谁
And no one knew who I was the last time I came either.
夫人 注意
My Lady.
欢迎来到君临 史塔克夫人 可否随我们走一趟？
Welcome to King's Landing, Lady Stark. Would you mind following us?
为什么？我们没犯什么事啊
I would. We've done nothing wrong.
我们奉命护送您进城
We've been instructed to escort you into the city.
奉命？
Instructed?
奉谁的命？这是…
I don't know who's providing your instructions, but--
请随我来 史塔克夫人
follow me, Lady Stark.
凯特！你们退下
Cat! Go on.
上楼去
Go upstairs.
你这小瘪三
You little worm!
当我是暗巷里的婊子吗？
You take me for some back-alley Sally
你竟敢把我带到…
you can drag into a--
去去！
pssst!
我没有不敬之意
I meant no disrespect
尤其是对你
to you of all people.
你竟敢把我带到这种地方！
How dare you bring me here!
你疯了不成？
Have you lost your mind?
没人会上这儿来找你 这不正是你所期望的吗？
No one will come looking for you here. Isn't that what you wanted?
安排在此地见面我表示歉意
I'm truly sorry about the locale.
你怎么知道我来了君临？
How did you know I was coming to King's Landing?
一位好朋友告诉我的
A dear friend told me.
- 史塔克夫人 - 瓦里斯伯爵
- Lady Stark. - Lord Varys.
阔别多年 今日相见真是令人欢欣鼓舞
To see you again after so many years is a blessing.
哎呀 您的手是怎么了？
Your poor hands.
你怎会知道我来了？
How did you know I was coming?
我的职责便是打听消息啊 好夫人
Knowledge is my trade, my Lady.
我在想 您是否把那把匕首也带来啦？
Did you bring the dagger with you, by any chance?
我的小小鸟儿无处不在
My little birds are everywhere...
即便是发生在北境的奇怪故事
Even in the North.
他们也给我传回来了
They whisper to me the strangest stories.
瓦雷利亚钢
Valyrian steel.
你知道匕首的主人是谁？
Do you know whose dagger this is?
毫无头绪
I must admit I do not.
哈哈 这真是历史性的一刻
Well well, this is an historic day.
我居然会知道
Something you don't know
你不知道的事情
that I do.
放眼七大王国 这匕首只有一把
There's only one dagger like this in all of the Seven Kingdoms.
- 它是我的 - 你的？
- It's mine. - Yours?
直到乔佛里王子命名日那天的比武大会为止
At least it was, until the tournament on Prince Joffrey's last Nameday.
我和所有有常识的人一样
I bet on Ser Jaime in the jousting,
赌詹姆爵士会赢得长枪比试
as any sane man would.
所以当百花骑士把他刺下马时
When the Knight of the Flowers unseated him,
我输掉了这把匕首
I lost this dagger.
输给谁？
To whom?
提利昂·兰尼斯特
Tyrion Lannister.
小恶魔
The imp.
葛兰 让他见识见识农民的本事
Grenn, show him what you farm boys are made of.
如果是真剑 你早没命了
If that were a real sword, you'd be dead.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人 临冬城公爵的私生子
咱们的雪诺大人可是长在城堡里
Lord Snow here grew up in a castle
你们只配被他唾弃
spitting down on the likes of you.
派普！
Pyp.
艾里沙·索恩
黑城堡的守夜人教头
你认为奈德·史塔克的野种
Do you think Ned Stark's bastard
会跟你们一样流血吗？
bleeds like the rest of us?
下一个！
Next!
好吧 雪诺大人
Well, Lord Snow,
看来你是这帮饭桶里最结实的一个
it appears you're the least useless person here.
去把自己收拾干净
Go clean yourselves up.
我今天已经看够了
There's only so much I can stomach in a day.
好有魅力的教头
A charming man.
他有没有魅力不重要
I don't need him to be charming.
他能不能将这帮窃贼逃犯
I need him to turn this bunch of thieves and runaways
训练成守夜人军团的汉子才是关键
into men of The Night's Watch.
那他进展如何呢 莫尔蒙司令？
And how's that going, commander Mormont?
杰奥·莫尔蒙
守夜人总司令
慢慢来吧
Slowly.
有信鸦
A raven came
带来奈德·史塔克儿子的消息
for Ned Stark's son.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
王后幼弟 "小恶魔"
是好是坏？
Good news or bad?
喜忧参半罢
Both.
史塔克大人
Lord Stark.
我本想早点给你的
I meant to give you this earlier.
最近忘性太大
So forgetful these days.
今天早上有信鸦从临冬城飞来
A raven from Winterfell this morning.
好消息？
Good news?
或许您想与夫人分享吧？
Perhaps you'd like to share it with your wife?
- 我夫人人在临冬城 - 是吗？
- My wife is in Winterfell. - Is she?
是你 我看的就是你
Yes, I'm looking at you.
这家店恰好是由我经营
I thought that she'd be safest in here.
你老婆在这里最安全
One of several such establishments I own.
你真会开玩笑
You're a funny man.
嗯？你觉得很好笑是不是？
Huh? A very funny man.
奈德！
Ned!
啊 这帮姓史塔克的…
Ah, the Starks--
爆脾气 死脑筋
quick tempers, slow minds.
小杂种 你打破了我的鼻子！
You broke my nose, bastard!
就当给你整容吧
It's an improvement.
葛兰
守夜人
把你从长城上扔下去 要多久才会着地呢？
If we threw you over The Wall, I wonder how long it would take you to hit.
我怀疑他们能不能在野狼光顾前找到你的尸体
I wonder if they'd find you before the wolves did.
你看什么看 半人？
What're you looking at, half man?
我在看你啊
I'm looking at you.
真的
Yes.
雷斯特
守夜人
你的脸很有特点
You've got an interesting face.
嗯 令人过目难忘
Hmm, very distinctive faces.
你们长得都不错
All of you.
我们长什么样关你屁事？
And what do you care about our faces?
把这么几颗有特点的脑袋插在枪上
It's just I think they would look marvelous
来装饰君临的城门挺不错
decorating spikes in King's Landing.
或许我该写信给我老姐 跟她分享这个点子
Perhaps I'll write my sister, the Queen, about it.
我们走着瞧 雪诺大人
We'll talk later, Lord Snow.
大家都知道这是个什么地方
Everybody knew what this place was
但没人告诉我真相
and no one told me.
除了你
No one but you.
我父亲肯定知情
My father knew
却仍然把我送来自生自灭
and he left me to rot at The Wall all the same.
葛兰的父亲
Grenn's father left him too...
在他三岁那年就把他丢到了农场外面
Outside a farmhouse when he was three.
派普尔
守夜人 亦称“派普”
派普不过偷了一轮奶酪
Pyp was caught stealing a wheel of cheese.
她老妹当时三天没吃饭了
His little sister hadn't eaten in three days.
他不想失去右手的话 就得来长城充军
He was given a choice: His right hand or The Wall.
我这两天都在跟总司令聊他们的故事
I've been asking the lord commander about them.
迷人的故事
Fascinating stories.
他们恨我 因为我比他们优秀
They hate me because I'm better than they are.
你很幸运 因为他们都没机会
It's a lucky thing none of them were trained
接受临冬城教头罗德利克爵士的训练
by a Master-at-Arms like your Ser Rodrik.
我甚至敢断言
I don't imagine any of them have ever held a real sword
来这里之前 他们都没握过真剑
before they came here.
对了…
Oh...
你弟弟布兰
Your brother Bran.
他醒了
He's woken up.
哪怕只是暗示王后的弟弟涉嫌谋害你儿子
The mere suggestion that the queen's brother
便已构成叛国罪
tried to kill your boy would be considered treason.
我们有证据 我们有这把匕首
We have proof. We have the blade.
提利昂大人肯定会辩称匕首是被偷的
Which Lord Tyrion will say was stolen from him.
托你儿子那只狼的福
The only man who could say otherwise has no throat,
惟一能戳穿他的人被咬断了喉咙
thanks to your boy's wolf.
培提尔答应协助我们调查真相
Petyr has promised to help us find the truth.
他就像我失散多年的弟弟 奈德
He's like a little brother to me, Ned.
他不会辜负我的信任
He would never betray my trust.
为着她的缘故 我会尽量不让你送命
I'll try to keep you alive, for her sake.
说来只有笨蛋才会这么做
A fool's task, admittedly,
但我就是没法拒绝你老婆的任何请求
but I've never been able to refuse your wife anything.
我不会忘记你的帮助
I won't forget this.
你是一个真正的朋友
You're a true friend.
这话你可千万别告诉他人 免得我辛苦建立的名声毁于一旦
Don't tell anyone. I have a reputation to maintain.
- 你怎能如此愚蠢？ - 冷静点
- How could you be so stupid? - Calm down.
他是个孩子 他才十岁
He's a child-- 10 years old.
- 你当时想什么呢？ - 想咱俩啊
- What were you thinking? - I was thinking of us.
况且你现在抱怨怕是太迟了吧
You're a bit late to start complaining about it now.
- 那男孩到底说了什么？ - 什么也没说
- What has the boy told them? - Nothing.
他什么也不记得了
He's said nothing. He remembers nothing.
那你吵什么吵？
Then what are you raving about?
万一他想起来了呢？
What if it comes back to him?
如果他把当时的情景告诉他父亲…
If he tells his father what he saw--
我们就说他在发梦 在骗人
we'll say he was lying. We'll say he was dreaming.
我们怎么说都行
We'll say whatever we like.
还怕一个十岁孩子不成
I think we can outfox a 10-year-old.
- 你有没有想过我丈夫？ - 他么 必要时我跟他拼命
- And my husband? - I'll go to war with him if I have to.
歌手们说不定会写首歌
They can write a ballad about us:
《瑟曦的阴道之战》
"The War for Cersei's Cunt."
- 放开我 - 才不
- Let me go. - Never.
放开我
Let me go.
那男孩不会说的
The boy won't talk.
如果他说出去 我就先宰了他
And if he does, I'll kill him.
再干掉奈德·史塔克 国王…把他们杀干净
Him, Ned Stark, the king- the whole bloody lot of them,
直到天底下
until you and I are the only people
只剩你和我
left in this world.
我本想见见女儿们
I wish I could see the girls.
- 太冒险了 - 就看一眼…
- It's too dangerous. - Just for a moment.
等我们弄清敌人是谁再说吧
Until we know who our enemies are--
肯定是他们干的 奈德 是兰尼斯特
I know they did it, Ned. The Lannisters.
我打骨子里知道是他们干的
In my bones, I know it.
小指头有一点说得对
Littlefinger's right.
没有证据 我什么也做不了
I can't do anything without proof.
等你找到了证据…
And if you find the proof?
我将晋见劳勃
Then I bring it to Robert...
并期望他仍保有往日的英明
And hope he's still the man I once knew.
路上当心 嗯？
You watch yourself on the road, huh?
你脾气不好
That temper of yours is a dangerous thing.
我脾气不好？诸神在上
My temper? Gods be good,
是谁昨天差点错杀可怜的小指头？
you nearly killed poor Littlefinger yesterday.
他还对你恋恋不忘呢
He still loves you.
是吗？
Does he?
别了
Off with you.
劳勃·拜拉席恩
国王
啊 过了这么多年
Yes, it's been a long time.
但每一张脸我都记得
But I still remember every face.
你记得你杀的第一个人吗?
You remember your first?
记得 陛下
Of course, Your Grace.
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
御林铁卫队长
是谁？
Who was it?
一个泰洛西人
A Tyroshi.
没问过名字
Never learned the name.
怎么杀的？
How'd you do it?
一枪穿心
Lance through the heart.
干脆利落
Quick one.
你真走运
Lucky for you.
我第一次杀人是在盛夏厅之战 对方是塔利家的小子
Mine was some Tarly boy at the Battle of Summerhall.
我的坐骑中箭 所以我徒步作战
My horse took an arrow so I was on foot,
蹚着泥浆蹒跚前进
slogging through the mud.
这不开眼的名门之子 就这么直挺挺地朝我冲来
He came running at me, this dumb high-born lad,
满以为可以凭借手中长剑
thinking he could end the rebellion
一举终结叛乱
with single swing of his sword.
我用战锤把他撂下马来
I knocked him down with the hammer.
诸神在上 我当年可真壮！
Gods, I was strong then.
那一锤砸扁了他的胸甲
Caved in his breastplate.
大概把他每一根肋骨都打断了
Probably shattered every rib he had.
我踩在他身上 抡起锤子
Stood over him, hammer in the air.
就听他大喊：“等等！”
Right before I brought it down he shouted, "wait!
“等等！”
Wait."
唱歌的从来不说将死之人是怎么被吓得屎尿齐流
They never tell you how they all shit themselves.
歌谣里也不会把这些写进去
They don't put that part in the songs.
真是个傻孩子
Stupid boy.
后来塔利家族和其他人一样
Now the Tarlys bend the knee
屈膝称臣
like everyone else.
他应该和那些聪明的孩子一起
He could have lingered
远远地躲在战场边缘
on the edge of the battle with the smart boys
今天他才有资本嫌弃自己臭脾气的老婆
and today his wife would be making him miserable,
和忘本的孩子
his sons would be ingrates,
每天夜里起来三遍
and he'd be waking three times in the night
找把夜壶撒尿 倒酒！
to piss into a bowl. Wine!
蓝赛尔 诸神在上 好个蠢名字
Lancel. Gods, what a stupid name.
蓝赛尔·兰尼斯特？
Lancel Lannister.
蓝赛尔·兰尼斯特
王后的堂弟
哪个大舌头替你取的？太他妈蠢了！
Who named you? Some halfwit with a stutter?
你愣着干嘛？
What are you doing?
- 酒壶空了 陛下 - 什么叫空了？
- It's empty, Your Grace. - What do you mean it's empty?
- 里面没有酒了 - 这就叫空了？
- There's no more wine. - Is that what empty means?
没有酒就去取啊！
So get more.
顺便把你堂哥给我叫进来
Tell your cousin to get in here.
弑君者！
Kingslayer!
给我进来！
Get in here.
身边净他妈是些兰尼斯特
Surrounded by Lannisters.
合上眼睛看见的还是他们的金发
Every time I close my eyes I see their blond hair
和那自鸣得意的傲慢嘴脸
and their smug, satisfied faces.
干这活儿伤你自尊了吧？
It must wound your pride, huh?
好一副气宇轩昂的风采…
Standing out there like a glorified sentry.
詹姆·兰尼斯特 伟大的泰温之子…
Jaime Lannister, son of the mighty Tywin...
他的国王在里面吃喝拉撒玩女人
Forced to mind the door while your King
他却在外头看着一扇傻不拉叽的房门
eats and drinks and shits and fucks.
说说看
So come on.
我们在聊打仗的事
We're telling war stories.
除了老弱病残 你杀的第一个人是谁?
Who was your first kill, not counting old men?
是一名御林兄弟会的土匪
One of the outlaws in the Brotherhood.
那天我在场
I was there that day.
你才十六岁 是个侍从
You were only a squire, 16 years old.
而你用一招回旋剑结果了西蒙·托因
You killed Simon Toyne with a counter riposte.
我没见过那么漂亮的招式
Best move I ever saw.
托因是个好战士 可惜他体力不支
A good fighter, Toyne, but he lacked stamina.
你那土匪…
Your outlaw...
有什么遗言吗？
Any last words?
没有 我一剑砍了他脑袋
I cut his head off, so no.
那伊里斯·坦格利安呢？
What about Aerys Targaryen?
被你背后捅刀的疯王有什么遗言？
What did the Mad King say when you stabbed him in the back?
我没问他
I never asked.
他有没有骂你是叛徒？
Did he call you a traitor?
有没有求你饶命啊？
Did he plead for a reprieve?
他念叨着他念叨了一整天的话…
He said the same thing he'd been saying for hours...
“烧死他们”
"Burn them all."
如果没事了 陛下…
If that's all, Your Grace...
多斯拉克人的奴隶是买来的吗？
Do the Dothraki buy their slaves?
多斯拉克人没有金钱观念
The Dothraki don't believe in money.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
杰奥·莫尔蒙之子
大多数奴隶是当礼物送给他们的
Most of their slaves were given to them as gifts.
- 谁送的？ - 作为城邦统治者
- From whom? - If you rule a city
当马上民族来袭时 有两个选择：
and you see the horde approaching, you have two choices:
要么进贡 要么拼命
Pay tribute or fight.
答案显而易见
An easy choice for most.
当然 不是进贡就万事大吉
Of course, sometimes it's not enough.
有时卡奥们觉得献上的奴隶太少 令他蒙羞
Sometimes a Khal feels insulted by the number of slaves he's given.
或者男奴太弱 女奴太丑
He might think the men too weak or the women too ugly.
有时卡奥们认为麾下的骑马战士好久没开杀戒了
Sometimes a Khal decides his riders haven't had a good fight in months
需要满足欲望
and need the practice.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
卡丽熙
叫他们全部停下
Tell them all to stop.
你要整个部落停下？
You want the entire horde to stop?
停多久?
For how long?
直到我下令开拔为止
Until I command them otherwise.
你说话越来越像个公主了
You're learning to talk like a Queen.
不是公主
Not a Queen.
是卡丽熙
A Khaleesi.
Annakhas dozgosores.
全部停下
Stop the horde.
你好大的胆子！
You dare!
你竟敢命令我？命令我？
You give commands to me? To me?
你竟敢对真龙之子颐指气使 我可是七国之君
You do not command the Dragon. I am Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
蛮子和蛮子的小贱货没资格命令我
I don't take orders from savages
韦赛里斯·坦格利安
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的二哥
你听见了没有？
or their sluts. Do you hear me?
Hash shafka zali addrivat mae,zhey Khaleesi?
您要他的命吗？卡莉熙
Do you want him dead khaleesi?
卡丽熙 拉卡洛问您是否要他死
Rakharo ask if you want him dead, Khaleesi.
不要
No.
拉卡洛
血盟卫
Ishish chare acharoe hash me nem ejervae nharesoon.
割他一只耳朵才能让他听得进话
Maybe the ear will listen if it is removed from the head.
拉卡洛认为您应该割他一只耳朵给他一个教训
Rakharo say you should take ear,to teach respect.
别伤害他 请别伤害他
Please please, don't hurt him.
跟他说我不希望我哥哥受伤害
Tell him I don't want my brother harmed.
Khaleesi vos zalo meme nem vazzisa.
卡莉熙不愿他受到伤害
Khaleesi does not want him harmed.
伊丽
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
Chiftik!
窝囊废！
Cricket!
莫尔蒙！把这些多斯拉克狗杀了！
Mormont! Kill these Dothraki dogs!
我是你的国王！
I am your King!
回去跟卡拉萨汇合吧 卡丽熙？
Shall we return to the Khalasar, Khaleesi?
你 走路
You walk.
我想在这陪你看第一眼
I wanted to be here when you saw it for the first time.
班扬·史塔克
临冬城公爵之弟 守夜人的首席游骑兵
- 我破晓时就要走了 - 你要走？
- I'm leaving this morning. - You're leaving?
我是首席游骑兵
I'm the First Ranger.
职责在长城之外
My job is out there.
- 近来有些令人不安的报告 - 什么样的报告?
- There have been disturbing reports. - What kind of reports?
我不愿相信的报告
The kind I don't want to believe.
我随你同去 我不会让你失望的
I'm ready. I won't let you down.
你不能去
You're not going.
琼恩 你还不是游骑兵
You're no Ranger, Jon.
- 可我比他们都强… - 你不比任何人强！
- But I'm better than every-- - Better than no one!
在这里…
Here...
想得到什么样的待遇
A man gets what he earns,
就得证明自己有什么样的本事
when he earns it.
等我回来再谈
We'll speak when I return.
- 熊的蛋蛋 加上… - 噢 别逗了
- A bear's balls. - Oh, you're joking?
加上它的脑子 肠子和心肺
And his brains and his guts, his lungs and his heart
用它身上的油煎熟了
all fried in his own fat.
当你身处绝境长城之外
When you're a hundred miles North of The Wall
一个星期没饭吃的时候 你什么也不会给狼剩下
and you ate your last meal a week ago, you leave nothing for the wolves.
熊的蛋蛋是个什么味道啊？
And how do a bear's balls taste?
有点难嚼
A bit chewy.
你呢 大人？你吃过的最古怪的东西是啥？
And what about you, my Lord? What's the strangest thing you've eaten?
多恩娘们算吗？
Do Dornish girls count?
所以说 你周游七国
So you roam the Seven Kingdoms,
招揽摸包贼和盗马贼
collaring pickpockets and horse thieves
介绍来这里当兵喽？
and bringing them here as eager recruits?
不错
Aye.
尤伦
守夜人 “浪鸦”
他们也不全是罪犯啦
But it's not all of 'em's done bad things.
有时会遇上吃不饱饭的穷孩子
Some of 'em's just poor lads looking for steady feed.
有时会遇上渴望出人头地的贵族青年
Some of 'em's high-born lads looking for glory.
结果他们发现在这儿混口饭吃还比较靠谱 对吧？
They have a better chance finding feed than glory.
守夜人军团在你眼中就是个笑话 是不？
The Night's Watch is a joke to you, is it?
兰尼斯特 你是不是觉得我们
Is that what we are, Lannister?
是一支可笑的黑衣杂技团？
An army of jesters in black?
错 你们的人手不足以成团
You don't have enough men to be an army
而且除了这个尤伦 也没有谁特别搞笑
and aside from Yoren here, none of you are particularly funny.
我希望你回到君临后
I hope we've provided you with some good stories to tell
能把我们真实的故事讲给别人听
when you're back in King's Landing.
在你饮酒作乐
But something to think about
寻花问柳的时候
while you're drinking your wine down there,
偶尔也能摸摸良心
enjoying your brothels--
在这里受训的孩子 将来有很多会葬身于长城之外
half the boys you've seen training will die North of The Wall.
他们有的逃不过野人的斧头
Might be a Wilding's axe that gets them,
有的是病死
might be sickness,
还有的被严寒夺去性命
might just be the cold.
他们死得很痛苦
They die in pain.
正因为他们的牺牲奉献
And they do it so plump little lords like you
你们这帮脑满肠肥的老爷才能享受夏日午后的憩静
can enjoy their summer afternoons in peace and comfort.
你觉得我算脑满肠肥吗？
Do you think I'm plump?
听着 班杨…我能叫你班杨吗？
Listen, Benjen-- may I call you Benjen?
随便你
Call me what you like.
我不晓得我哪里冒犯了你
I'm not sure what I've done to offend you.
但我郑重声明我非常尊敬守夜人军团
I have great admiration for The Night's Watch.
尊敬身为首席游骑兵的你
I've great admiration for you as First Ranger.
知道吗 我哥哥曾告诉我
You know, my brother once told me
在“但是”之前所做的声明
that nothing someone says before the word "but"
全是狗屁
really counts.
好吧…但是
But...
我不相信长城之外
I don't believe that Giants and Ghouls and White Walkers
有巨人 尸鬼或是什么异鬼
are lurking beyond The Wall.
我认为我们和
I believe that the only difference
野人的区别只在于
between us and the Wildlings is that
当长城拔地而起时 我们的祖先
when The Wall went up, our ancestors happened
碰巧住在正确的一边
to live on the right side of it.
这点你说得对
You're right.
野人和我们没什么差别
The Wildlings are no different from us.
可能更彪悍一些
A little rougher maybe.
但终究是血肉之躯
But they're made of meat and bone.
我知道怎么追踪 怎么杀死他们
I know how to track them and I know how to kill them.
搅得我辗转难眠的并非野人
It's not the Wildlings giving me sleepless nights.
你没有去过长城之北
You've never been North of The Wall,
就不要不懂装懂
so don't tell me what's out there.
你要下去了?
Are you going below?
- 请保重 保暖 - 在都城好好享受 兄弟
- Keep well, keep warm. - Enjoy the capital, brother.
我总是很享受
Oh, I always do.
我觉得他喜欢上我了
I think he's starting to like me.
- “下去”是什么意思？ - 啊
- "Going below"? - Aye.
下隧道
Into the tunnel
穿到另一头去
and out the other side.
他会在长城北边呆上一两个月
He'll be North of The Wall for a month or two.
他这么说 你要南下君临？
So you're heading down to King's Landing too.
对 后天启程
Aye, day after tomorrow.
这儿一半的人来自君临的地牢
I get about half of my recruits from their dungeons.
不妨同路吧 你是个好伴儿
Let's share the road. I could use some decent company.
大人 我…我可是一贯风餐露宿的啊
I... I travel a bit on the grubby side, my Lord.
这回不必了
Not this time.
我们会住最好的城堡和旅店
We'll be staying at the finest castles and inns.
没有人敢怠慢兰尼斯特家的人
No one turns away a Lannister.
Athjahakar
勇武
Pride,prowess.
这回说对了 卡丽熙
Yes, Khaleesi.
喔 你这是做什么？
Oh, what are you doing?
卡丽熙 您上次来月事是什么时候?
When was last time you bleed, Khaleesi?
您有身孕了 卡丽熙
You change, Khaleesi.
Me azhasavva vezhofoon.
这是圣马的祝福啊
It's a blessing from the great stallion.
对马上民族来说
For a man on horseback, the curved blade
弯刀是好东西 易于掌控
is a good thing, easier to handle.
对付你的多斯拉克同胞很顺手
It's a good weapon for a Dothrakan.
但要对付穿全身板甲的人…
But a man in full plate--
shori tawakof.
铁衣服
steel dress.
亚拉克弯刀穿不透甲胄
the arakh won't get through the steel.
这时阔剑就派上用场了
That's where the broadsword has the advantage.
它是为了刺穿盔甲而设计的
Designed for piercing plate.
Dothraki vos ondeo shoris tawakofi.
我们多斯拉克人不穿铁衣服
Dothraki don't wear steel dresses.
- 盔甲 - 盔甲
- Armor. - Armor.
盔甲使人行动…
Armor make a man...
缓慢
Slow.
- 缓慢 - 没错
- Slow. - It's true,
但也能保人性命
but it also keeps a man alive.
Ave anni ezzo anhaan os lajataan.
我父亲教会我如何战斗
My father taught me how to fight.
Me ezzo anhaan m'athdikar assie athzhokwazar.
他说速度比力量重要
He taught me that speed defeats size.
Anha ray char m'ave yeri lajakoon hakeso.
听说你父亲是著名的勇士
I heard that your father was a famous warrior.
Me dothrakhqoyoon torga Khali Bharbo.
他是拔尔勃卡奥的血盟卫
He was bloodrider to Khal Bharbo.
Majin ave yeri Jorah Andahli? Hash me lajakoon akka?
安达尔人乔拉 你父亲呢 他也是位勇士吗？
And your father, Jorah the Andal? He was a warrior also?
他仍然是
He still is.
他是个荣誉感极强的人
A man of great honor
我却背叛了他…
and I betrayed him.
Khaleesi zala meme adakha esinakh ajjalan.
卡丽熙今晚想换换口味
The khaleesi wants to eat something different tonight.
Ogi loy mawizzi.
去弄兔子肉
Kill some rabbits.
Vo mawizzi vekho jinne.
哪来的兔子
There are no rabbits.
Ezas loy alegri h'anhaan. Mori allayafi mae, jin alegra.
那就搞几只鸭子 她爱吃鸭子
Find some ducks for me. She likes ducks.
Hash yer ray tih loy alegri zhey vikeesi? Vo mawizzi, vo alegri.
你在这里见过鸭子吗 蠢女人? 没兔子 没鸭子
Have you seen any ducks, woman? No rabbits, no ducks.
Hash tihi vekhi she nhare yeroon? Hash tih?
你到底长眼睛没？啊？
Do you have eyes in your head? Do you?
Majin jano. Anha ray tih san jani.
那就杀只狗吧 狗我见过不少
Dogs then. I have seen many dogs.
我记得她不喜欢狗肉
I don't think she wants to eat dog.
卡丽熙怀上孩子了
The Khaleesi have baby inside her.
是真的 她已经两个月没来月事了
It is true. She does not bleed for two moons.
肚子也鼓起来了
Her belly start to swell.
A blessing from the great stallion.
圣马的祝福啊
她实在不想再吃马肉了
She does not want to eat horse.
我让他们宰只山羊当晚餐好了
I'll have the boys butcher a goat for supper.
我要去科霍尔走一趟
I need to ride to Qohor.
呃 可我们正向维斯·多斯拉克进发啊
Uh, we ride for Vaes Dothrak.
别担心 我会赶上来的
Don't worry. I'll catch you.
这么大的部落容易找
The horde's easy to find.
你别站死了
Don't stand so still.
动起来才不容易被击中
It's harder to hit a moving target.
你正相反 你动作太频繁
Except for you. You move too much.
有时候自己都能撞我剑上
I could just hold my sword out and let you do the work for me.
你经历过几个冬天 提利昂大人？
How many winters have you seen, Lord Tyrion?
八个…不 九个
Eight-- no, nine.
而且都不长 对吧？
All of them brief?
据说我降生时的冬天持续了整整三年 伊蒙师傅
They say the winter of my birth was three years long, Maester Aemon.
这个夏天已经过了九年
This summer has lasted nine.
而学城的报告证明白昼已经渐渐缩短
But reports from the Citadel tell us the days grow shorter.
史塔克的族语终究是要应验的：
The Starks are always right eventually:
凛冬将至
Winter is coming.
伊蒙·坦格利安
守夜人的学士
这次的冬季将十分漫长
This one will be long
随之降临的是黑暗的年代
and dark things will come with it.
我们最近抓到了很多野人
We've been capturing Wildlings,
他们正向南逃亡 数量逐月增加
more every month. They're fleeing south.
他们声称见到了走动的异鬼
The ones who flee say they've seen the White Walkers.
是啊 兰尼斯港的渔夫还经常看到美人鱼呢
Yes, and the fishermen of Lannisport say they see mermaids.
一位守夜人游骑兵坚称自己的同伴为异鬼所害
One of our own Rangers swore he saw them kill his companions.
奈德·史塔克砍他脑袋时
He swore it right up to the moment
他仍不改口
Ned Stark chopped his head off.
守夜人部队是唯一
The Night's Watch is the only thing
能帮助王国阻挡
standing between the realm
北方黑暗势力的屏障
and what lies beyond.
而它现在却是
And it has has become an army
由毛头小子和身心俱疲的老头子组成
of undisciplined boys and tired old men.
我们的人数不到一千
There are less than a thousand of us now.
无力守卫长城沿线的堡垒
We can't man the other castles on The Wall.
无法保证巡逻任务的质量
We can't properly patrol the wilderness.
我们所拥有的资源 仅能勉强维持温饱
We've barely enough resources to keep our lads armed
- 并武装自己 - 令姐
- and fed. - Your sister
贵为当今王后
sits by the side the King.
请代我们向她请愿
Tell her we need help.
当凛冬降临时
When winter does come,
若没有万全准备 天知道下场会多凄惨
gods help us all if we're not ready.
Me rakh.
是个男孩
It's a boy.
Kifinosi yer nesi?
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
卓戈 卡奥
多斯拉克部族首领
Anha sekke nesa.
我能感觉到
I very knows.
真有些舍不得你走 兰尼斯特
I'm sorry to see you leave, Lannister.
我跟这鬼天气似乎结下了梁子
It's either me or this cold.
它不肯让路 我只有乖乖滚蛋喽
And it doesn't appear to be going anywhere.
你南下途中会在临冬城稍事停留吗？
Will you stop at Winterfell on your way south?
应该会
I expect I will.
诸神在上 君临和长城之间
Gods know there aren't many feather beds
可没几张羽毛床
between here and King's Landing.
如果你见到我弟弟布兰
If you see my brother Bran,
告诉他我很想他
tell him I miss him.
告诉他我一有机会就去看他
Tell him I'd visit if I could.
没问题
Of course.
他的双腿没法复原了
He'll never walk again.
如果不幸做了瘸子
If you're going to be a cripple,
当个贵族家的瘸子总归要好些
it's better to be a rich cripple.
你自己当心 雪诺
You take care, Snow.
再会 大人
Farewell, my Lord.
小子 你迟到了
You are late, boy.
从明天起你正午就必须到
Tomorrow you will be here at midday.
你是谁？
Who are you?
西利欧·佛瑞尔
布拉佛斯剑术家
你的舞蹈老师
Your dancing master,
西利欧·佛瑞尔
Syrio Forel.
从明天起你得接住
Tomorrow you will catch it.
现在捡起来
Now pick it up.
不对不对 小子
That is not the way, boy.
这不是双手挥的巨剑
This is not a greatsword that is needing two hands to swing it.
- 它太重了 - 它该多重就有多重
- It's too heavy. - It is heavy as it needs to be
这才能锻炼你的肌肉
to make you strong.
就是这样
Just so.
你只能单手持剑
One hand is all that is needed.
但你的站姿错了
Now you are standing all wrong.
身体侧一点
Turn your body sideface.
对
Yes.
就是这样
So.
你很瘦 这挺好
You are skinny. That is good.
目标缩小了
The target is smaller.
现在让我看看你是怎么握的
Now the grip-- let me see.
对
Yes.
手型要优雅
The grip must be delicate.
剑掉了怎么办？
What if I drop it?
剑必须和你的手合为一体
The steel must be part of your arm.
你的手会掉吗？当然不会
Can you drop part of your arm? No.
西利欧·佛瑞尔在布拉佛斯海王手下干了九年的首席剑士
Nine years Syrio Forel was first sword to the Sealord of Braavos.
他懂得这些东西 听他的话 小子
He knows these things. You must listen to me, boy.
我是女生
I'm a girl.
管他男的女的 你是一把剑
Boy, girl-- you are a sword,
这样就够了
that is all.
保持这个握姿
That is the grip.
你握的不是战斧
You are not holding a battle-axe.
- 你握的是… - 缝衣针
- You are holding-- - A Needle.
就是这样
Just so.
现在我们开始跳舞
Now we will begin the dance.
记住 孩子
Remember, child,
我们学的不是维斯特洛的钢铁之舞
this is not the dance of the Westeros we are learning--
骑士之舞
the Knight's Dance,
挥来砍去
hacking and hammering.
这是杀手之舞
This is the Bravo's Dance...
水之舞
The Water Dance.
行动敏捷
It is swift
出其不意
and sudden.
人都是水做的
All men are made of water,
你知道吗？
do you know this?
当你刺中人体
If you pierce them,
水流外泄 人就会死
the water leaks out and they die.
现在你来打我试试
Now you will try to strike me.
哈！
Ha!
起来！
Up!
哈！
Ha!
你死了
Dead.
你又死了
Very dead.
来啊
Come.
再来 动作要快
Again, faster.
龙堡字幕组 & 衣柜字幕组 出品